Morning.
صباح الخير
Good morning, Komichi-san.
صباح الخير يا كوميتشي-سان
Good morning, Erika-chan.
صباح الخير يا إيريكا-تشان
By the way, I texted our pictures from the lake on Saturday to my dad.
بالمناسبة، أرسلتُ صورنا من البحيرة في يوم السّبت إلى أبي
To your dad?
إلى أبيكِ؟
He said he wished he could have gone fishing with us!
!قال بأنّه تمنّى لو ذهبَ لصيد السّمك معنا
He was surprised by the gear you had, too.
تفاجأ بالمعدّات التي كنتِ تمتلكينها أيضاً
H-He was? That's kind of embarrassing.
حـ-حقّاً؟ هذا محرج بعض الشيء
Oh, and he said you have very pretty hands!
!وقال بأنّ لديكِ يدان جميلتان جدّاً
H-He was even looking at that?
كـ-كان ينظر إلى ذلك حتّى؟
Well, you always keep your nails nice and tidy, right?
لأنّكِ دائماً ما تحافظين على نظافة ورتابة يديك، صحيح؟
So I told him...
...لذا أخبرتُه
It's because you're good at the violin!
!لأنّكِ بارعة في الكمان
It's so cool that you can play an instrument!
!من الرّائع جداً أن تتمكّني من العزف على آلة موسيقيّة
I wish I could do that!
!ليتني أستطيع فعل ذلك
I think it's far more amazing that you can dance.
أعتقد أنّ قدرتكِ على الرّقص مذهلة أكثر
Really?!
!حقّاً؟
Yes.
أجل
You're making me blush...
...أنتِ تحرجينني
Morning.
صباح الخير
Morning!
!صباح الخير
Okay, club time. Let's go.
حسناً، وقت النّادي. هيّا بنا
Episode Seven Please Let Me Hear It
الحلقة السّابعة دعيني أسمعه أرجوكِ
It's been a long day.
كان يوماً طويلاً
What're you changing into today?
ماذا سترتدين اليوم؟
Hey, nice!
!جميل
Yeah, when we're done.
أجل، عندما ننتهي
Well, see you later, Hebimori-san.
حسناً، أراك لاحقاً يا هيبيموري-سان
Uh... Yeah.
أجل
See ya.
إلى اللّقاء
Yeah, apparently.
أجل، على ما يبدو
Electric guitars sound so cool.
القيثارة الكهربائيّة تبدو رائعة للغاية
Oh, come on!
!بربّكِ
No, seriously, that was awesome!
!لا، بجدّية، كان ذلك مذهلاً
Just do it like that! It was great!
!افعليها بهذا الشكل فحسب! كان ذلك رائعاً
No way, I can't! It's too hard!
!مستحيل، لا أستطيع! هذا صعب جداً
Oh, sure you can!
!يمكنكِ بالتأكيد
But in the end, I chose not to join any clubs.
لكن في النهاية، اخترتُ عدم الانضمام لأيّ نادٍ
What? Ed ranked tenth? That makes no sense.
ماذا؟ إيد في المركز العاشر؟ هذا غير منطقيّ
The next issue is a special feature on Fukumoto Miki's youth?
العدد التّالي سيحتوي على مقالة خاصّة حول شباب فوكوموتو ميكي؟
Enough about Miki already.
كفى حديثاً عن ميكي
Oh, man, this Rara model's electric guitar is so cool.
القيثارة الكهربائيّة الخاصّة بنموذج رارا هذا رائعة للغاية
If I had that, I could...
...لو كنتُ أملكها، لكنتُ
Hebimori-san?
هيبيموري-سان؟
Hebimori-san.
هيبيموري-سان
Hebimori-san!
!هيبيموري-سان
Hello!
!مرحباً
Those are pretty hardcore.
إنّها مذهلة جدّاً
A-Akebi-san... Sorry, I didn't notice you there.
أ-أكيبي-سان... آسفة، لم ألحظ وجودكِ
Hebimori-san, isn't that...
...هيبيموري-سان، أليس هذا
That's a magazine that people who make music read, right?
هذه مجلّة يقرأها عازفو الموسيقى، صحيح؟
I bought a copy once because Miki-chan was on the cover!
اشتريتُ نسخة في السّابق لأنّ ميكي-تشان !موجودة في الغلاف
But when I got it home and opened it,
،لكن عندما أخذتُها إلى المنزل وفتحتُها
it was all sheet music inside.
لم أجد إلّا نوتة موسيقيّة في الدّاخل
I bought it because of the cover, so I didn't even notice.
اشتريتُها بسبب الغلاف، لذا لم ألحظ حتّى
I had no idea what any of it said.
لم أفهم كلّ ما جاء فيها
But does that mean you can play an instrument, too?
لكن هل هذا يعني أنّكِ تستطيعين العزف على آلة موسيقيّة أيضاً؟
Huh? Uh, not really.
ماذا؟ ليس تماماً
J-Just the guitar...
...الـ-القيثارة فقط
I guess.
أعتقد
Wow...
...مذهل
I wanna hear it!
!أريد سماعها
I want to hear you play guitar!
!أريد سماعكِ تعزفين على القيثارة
Sure.
حسناً
Testing, testing...
...اختبار، اختبار
Uh... Paging Akebi Komichi of Class 1-3.
استدعاء أكيبي كوميتشي من الصفّ 3-1
That's the club president!
!هذه هي رئيسة النّادي
Akebi Komichi, please report to your club room immediately.
أكيبي كوميتشي، الرّجاء الحضور إلى غرفة ناديك فوراً
Sorry! I gotta get to my club!
!آسفة! عليّ الذهاب إلى ناديّي
Let me hear you play sometime, okay?
دعيني أسمعكِ تعزفين يوماً ما، حسناً؟
Repeat: Akebi Komichi, Akebi Komichi, please repor—
—أكرّر: أكيبي كوميتشي، الرّجاء الحضور إلى
Well, now I've done it.
ها قد فعلتُها
I can't read sheet music at all.
لا أستطيع قراءة النوتات الموسيقيّة إطلاقاً
Mangetsu Dormitory
مسكن مانغيتسو
I brought my dad's old guitar with me from home for no particular reason,
أحضرتُ قيثارة أبي القديمة من المنزل ،بلا سبب محدّد
though I haven't played it once since I moved here.
مع أنّني لم أعزف عليها منذ انتقالي إلى هنا
It's not electric, after all.
فهي ليست كهربائيّة
Huh?
ماذا؟
Chords?
أوتار؟
Aren't music notes just "do, re, mi, fa," and so on?
أليست النوتات الموسيقيّة هي فقط "دو ري مي فا" وهكذا؟
Oh, here it is.
ها هي
First is... do...
...أوّلاً... دو
Okay, next...
...حسناً، التّالية
I did it!
!فعلتُها
Welcome back.
أهلاً بعودتكِ
Yeah.
نعم
I always thought that was just for decoration.
لطالما ظننتُ أنّ هذا للزينة فقط
Well, it was, but...
...كان كذلك، لكن
Oh, sorry. I'll only play it when you're not here.
آسفة. سأعزف عليه عندما لا تكونين هنا فقط
No, it's fine. It doesn't bother me.
لا، لا مشكلة. فهذا لا يزعجني
Okay...
...حسناً
Next, bend your knees, stretch your arms out wide,
،فيما يلي، اثني ركبتيكِ وابسطي ذراعيكِ
and bring your hands together above your head.
واجمعي يديكِ معاً فوق رأسكِ
Above your head!
!فوق رأسكِ
Now slowly bring your left leg forward.
والآن حرّكي ساقكِ اليسرى للأمام ببطء
Hebimori-san said she can play the guitar!
!قالت هيبيموري-سان أنّها تستطيع العزف على القيثارة
Does Hebimori-san play any instruments?
هل تعزف هيبيموري-سان على أيّ آلة موسيقيّة؟
Why don't you try playing an instrument, too?
لمَ لا تجرّبين العزف على آلة موسيقيّة أيضاً؟
Does Hebimori-san play any instruments?
!قالت هيبيموري-سان أنّها تستطيع العزف على القيثارة
Hebimori-san said she can play the guitar!
،والآن مدّي ساقيكِ بشكل واسع نحو كلّ طرف
and lean your upper body forward.
وانحني بالجزء العلويّ من جسدكِ للأمام
Music, huh?
موسيقى إذاً؟
That could be fun, too!
!قد يكون هذا ممتعاً أيضاً
Onee-chan! Focus!
!أونيه-تشان! ركّزي
Next, raise yourself up and...
...فيما يلي، ارفعي نفسكِ و
Next.
التّالية
Louder!
!أعلى
Good job today.
أحسنتُن صنعاً اليوم
Good job.
أحسنتُن صنعاً
Good job to you, too.
أحسنتِ صنعاً أيضاً
Okay.
حسناً
That's it for today.
يكفي لليوم
Okay... Thank you very much.
حسناً... شكراً جزيلاً لكِ
Wipe off all that sweat before you go home.
امسحي كلّ هذا العرق قبل أن تعودي إلى المنزل
You've been working hard.
كنتِ تعملين بجدّ ونشاط
T-Togano-san.
تـ-توغانو-سان
You're in the drama club, right?
أنتِ في نادي الدراما، صحيح؟
Do you always practice out here?
هل تتمرّنين هنا دائماً؟
No, it's usually in the lesson room,
،لا، هذا في غرفة الدروس عادة
but I've been trying the courtyard and other places lately.
لكن كنتُ أجرّب الفناء وأماكن أخرى مؤخّراً
Our club president said,
،قالت رئيسة نادينا ذات مرّة
"The first thing you need to get good at is using your voice in front of people."
أوّل شيء عليكِ أن تبرعي فيه هو استخدام" "صوتكِ أمام النّاس
That sounded like her.
هذا هو طبعها
This is my first time acting in a play,
،هذه أوّل مرّة أمثّل فيها في مسرحيّة
so she says I need lots of practice in the basics.
لذا تقول بأنّني بحاجة لكثير من التّمرين على الأساسيّات
I've been working on building up my... trunk? At home, too.
كنتُ أعمل على تطوير وتنمية... جذعي؟ في المنزل أيضاً
I think it's taking all I've got to keep up with my seniors, too.
أعتقد أستهلك كلّ ما لديّ لمُجاراة زميلاتي السّينباي أيضاً
Really?
حقّاً؟
But it's fun when you slowly learn to do something that you couldn't before, huh?
لكن من الممتع أن تتعلّمي القيام بشيء لم تستطيعي القيام به من قبل
Yeah.
أجل
By the way, you live in the same dorm room as Hebimori-san, right?
بالمناسبة، أنتِ تعيشين في نفس غرفة هيبيموري-سان في المسكن، صحيح؟
That's right.
هذا صحيح
Then I bet you've heard her play her guitar, right?
إذاً أنا واثقة بأنّكِ سمعتِها تعزف على قيثارتها، صحيح؟
G chord... uh...
...الوتر جي
First string, third fret...
...الوتر الأوّل، العتب الثّالث
Fifth string, second fret...
...الوتر الخامس، العتب الثّاني
Sixth string, third fret...
...الوتر السّادس، العتب الثّالث
Man, this is hard.
كم هذا صعب
Am I doing this right?
هل أفعل هذا بشكل صحيح؟
Well, whatever. Next is... C.
حسناً، أيّاً يكن. التّالي هو... سي
Second string, first fret...
...الوتر الثّاني، العتب الأوّل
Fourth string, second fret...
...الوتر الرّابع، العتب الثّاني
Fifth string, third fret...
...الوتر الخامس، العتب الثّالث
And sixth string... mute.
والوتر السّادس... كتم
Mute?
كتم؟
Just how many of these chords are there, anyway?
كم عدد هذه الأوتار على أيّ حال؟
How many guitar chords are there? Chords explained for beginners!
كم عدد أوتار القيثارة؟ !شرح الأوتار للمبتدئين
Guitar Teacher's Guitar Lesson
درس القيثارة من معلّم القيثارة
How many guitar chords are there? Chords explained for beginners!
كم عدد أوتار القيثارة؟ !شرح الأوتار للمبتدئين
Not a chance.
هذا غير ممكن
Well, it's not like I'll be using all of them.
حسناً، ليس وكأنّني سأستخدمها كلّها
If I just learn the necessary ones...
...إذا تعلّمتُ الضروريّة منها فقط
Welcome back.
أهلاً بعودتك
Thanks.
شكراً
You said a while ago that you liked this game, right?
قلتِ قبل قليل بأنّكِ أحببتِ هذه اللّعبة، صحيح؟
I saw Akebi-san after club practice today.
رأيتُ أكيبي-سان بعد تمرين النّادي اليوم
Y-Yeah?
حـ-حقّاً؟
She said she can't wait to hear you play guitar.
قالت بأنّها متحمّسة لسماعكِ تعزفين على القيثارة
You're not going to play it today?
لن تعزفي عليها اليوم؟
You know, apparently, there are a lot of different ways to play a guitar.
يبدو أنّ هناك الكثير من الطرق المختلفة للعزف على قيثارة
And a lot of it uses letters of the alphabet, like C and E.
والكثير منها تستخدم أحرفَ الأبجديّة مثل سي و إي
I'm having enough trouble just keeping up in class.
أواجه صعوبة بما يكفي لمُجاراة ما وصل إليه الصفّ
There's no way I can play guitar.
من المستحيل أن أتمكّن من العزف على القيثارة
Then shouldn't you tell Akebi-san that sooner rather than later?
إذاً ألا ينبغي أن تخبري أكيبي-سان بذلك عاجلاً غير آجل؟
I turned some screw-looking thing, and the string snapped.
سقط شيء يشبه المسمار وانكسر الوتر
Well, the strings were pretty rusty.
هذا طبيعي، فالأوتار صدِئة جدّاً
Yeah.
أجل
But that just proves what a complete newbie at this I am.
لكن هذا يثبت كم أنّني مبتدئة تماماً في هذا
What're you gonna do?
ماذا ستفعلين؟
Well, I want to learn how to play, but considering that...
،في الواقع، أريد أن أتعلّم كيفيّة العزف ...لكن بالنظر إلى ذلك
I guess it's too late to start now.
أعتقد فات الأوان على البدء الآن
I don't think anyone can master anything right off the bat.
لا يوجد شخص يستطيع إتقان أيّ شيء من البداية
That's why I practice every single day, too.
لهذا أتمرّن كلّ يوم أيضاً
I win again.
ربحتُ من جديد
You're so good at this, Togano-san.
أنتِ ماهرة جداً في هذا يا توغانو-سان
Nice! Over here!
!جميل! هنا
Good one!
!أحسنتِ
Okay, move your feet!
!حسناً، حرّكي قدميكِ
One more!
!من جديد
Oh, nice hit!
!إصابة مُوفّقة
Tatsumori-san is in the track club?
تاتسوموري-سان في نادي المضمار؟
Good, Akebi Komichi!
!جيّد يا أكيبي كوميتشي
Your voice should come from deep in your belly!
!ينبغي أن يصدر صوتكِ من أعماق بطنكِ
Akebi-san...
...أكيبي-سان
Your voice is sounding better than yesterday.
يبدو صوتكِ أفضل من الأمس
Look at how much she's sweating.
انظري إليها كم تتعرّق
Let's keep this up.
لنواظب على هذا
Okay!
!حسناً
But she looks kind of...
...لكنّها تبدو بعض الشيء
Good, Togano. Next practice, you'll take the court as a forward.
جيّد يا توغانو. في التّمرين المقبل، ستلعبين في مركز الهجوم في الملعب
Yes, ma'am!
!حاضرة
Togano-san, too.
توغانو-سان أيضاً
I did it!
!فعلتُها
beginner     guitar           song
أغنية     قيثارة           مبتدئ
All              Video       Images       News           Shopping
الكلّ              فيديو       صور       أخبار           تسوّق
[Guitar Practice Songs for Beginners] Play with simple chords...
[أغاني تمرين على القيثارة للمبتدئين] ...اعزف بأوتار بسيطة
[Guitar for Beginners] Play that famous song with arranged...
[قيثارة للمبتدئين] ...اعزف تلك الأغنية الشهيرة بتنسيق
You know, there was a time when I couldn't make a basket at all.
مرّت عليّ أوقات لم أكن أستطيع فيها إدخال الكرة في السلّة إطلاقاً
Because I was trying to make long shots right off the bat.
لأنّني كنتُ أحاول تحقيق رميات طويلة من البداية
Well, that's obviously too much.
لأنّ هذه حركة مكشوفة تماماً
I still miss all the time,
،ما زلتُ أخفق في تحقيق الإصابة طوال الوقت
but I started practicing shooting from closer to the net,
لكن بدأتُ أتمرّن على الرّمي من مسافات ،أقرب إلى الشّبكة
and gradually moved farther away from it.
ثمّ أخذتُ أبتعد عنها تدريجيّاً
So I'm sure there's something like that
لذا أنا متأكّدة أنّ هناك
for you to try, too.
ما تستطيعين تجربته أيضاً
I know this song.
أعرف هذه الأغنية
Are you ready to leave?
هل أنتِ جاهزة للمغادرة؟
Oh... Yeah.
أجل
Morning!
!صباح الخير
Morning.
صباح الخير
M-Morning.
صـ-صباح الخير
A-Akebi-san, will you have some time after school today?
أ-أكيبي-سان، هل ستكونين متفرّغة بعد دوام المدرسة اليوم؟
Here I am.
ها أنا ذي
I'm so excited, I'm getting nervous.
أنا متحمّسة جداً لدرجة التوتّر
Shouldn't that be my line?
ألا ينبغي أن تكون هذه عبارتي أنا؟
Oh, yeah!
!أجل
Okay... here I go.
حسناً... ها أنا ذي
Hey, Kizaki-san, there you are.
كيزاكي-سان، أنتِ هنا
O-Of course I am!
!بـ-بالطبع أنا كذلك
Erika-chan can play piano, too?
تجيد إيريكا-تشان العزف على البيانو أيضاً؟
I'm on cleaning duty this week.
دوري في واجب التّنظيف هذا الأسبوع
Oh, that's right.
هذا صحيح
So what did you want? I need to head to my club.
حسناً، ماذا أردتِ؟ عليّ الذّهاب إلى ناديّي
Aw, always so standoffish.
باردة دوماً
Ai was a little freaked out the other day, too.
كانت آي خائفة قليلاً قبل أيّام أيضاً
She said every time she goes to your room, you act like it's a bother,
قالت بأنّها كلّما ذهبت إلى غرفتكِ، تبدين منزعجة
so she asked if it was okay to bring you a notice from the dorm.
سألت ما إن لم يكن هناك مانع من إحضار إشعار لكِ من المسكن
So I told her that you're super scary when someone makes you mad.
لذا قلتُ لها بأنّكِ مخيفة جدّاً عندما يُغضبكِ أحد
D-Don't give people weird ideas!
!لـ-لا تعطي النّاس أفكاراً غريبة عنّي
But it's true, isn't it?
لكنّها صحيحة، أليس كذلك؟
I'm not like that to everyone.
لستُ هكذا مع الجميع
What?! You mean...
...ماذا؟! تقصدين
I've never seen Erika-chan act that way.
لم أرَ إيريكا-تشان تتصرّف هكذا من قبل
But her piano playing was beautiful.
لكن كان عزفها على البيانو جميلاً
Sorry.
آسفة
I'm really not up to it.
لستُ مستعدّة لذلك حقّاً
I can't follow a performance like that by Kizaki Erika.
لا أستطيع مُجاراة أداء كهذا بواسطة كيزاكي إيريكا
W-Wait!
!ا-انتظري
I lied to you, Akebi-san.
!كذبتُ عليكِ يا أكيبي-سان
The truth is... I can't play the guitar.
الحقيقة هي... أنّني لا أجيد العزف على القيثارة
So, bye.
لذا وداعاً
I want to hear it!
!أريد سماعه
Please let me hear it.
دعيني أسمعه أرجوكِ
I can't forget you
لا أستطيع نسيانك
As I walk this winding road
بينما أمشي في هذا الطريق الّذي تهبّ عليه الرّياح
With the newly-born sun
مع الشّمس المولودة حديثاً
And yellow sand that crosses over from my dreams
والرّمل الأصفر القادم من أحلامي
The day we fell over tickling each other
اليوم الّذي سقطنا فيه ندغدغ بعضنا الآخر
Will never come a second time
لن يتكرّر ثانية
I'm sure a livelier future than I ever imagined
أنا متأكّدة بأنّ مستقبلاً أكثر حيويّة ممّا نتخيّل
Is waiting for me
ينتظرني
Just the sound of "I love you"
"فقط صوت "أحبّك
Was enough to make me feel stronger
كان كافياً لأشعر نفسي أقوى
I embraced that tiny happiness
اعتنقتُ تلك السّعادة الصّغيرة
So tightly that I could have crushed it
ضممتُها بشدّة لدرجة كدتُ أسحقها
No, that's not right.
لا، هذا غير صحيح
I did it!
!فعلتُها
Did what?
فعلتُ ماذا؟
Oh, Togano-san...
...توغانو-سان
A-An F chord.
و-وتر ف
Oh... And?
وبعد؟
It's really important!
!إنّه مهمّ حقّاً
I'm gonna give her a much better performance than that next time!
!سأقدّم لها أداء أفضل بكثير من ذلك في المرّة المقبلة
Let me hear it again.
دعيني أسمغه من جديد
The F chord.
الوتر ف
Aw, jeez... Fine, I guess.
تبّاً... لا مشكلة على ما أعتقد
Roll, roll.
دحرجة، دحرجة
Today, I got to hear both Kizaki-san and Hebimori-san play their instruments.
اليوم، تمكّنتُ من سماع عزف كيزاكي-سان وهيبيموري-سان على آلتهما
And it made me feel like I need to work hard in the drama club, too.
وأشعرني ذلك بأنّ عليّ العمل بجدّ في نادي الدراما أيضاً
Roll, roll.
دحرجة، دحرجة
Onee-chan, it's about to start.
أونيه-تشان، إنّه على وشك البدء
Okay!
!حسناً
Next, bend your knees, stretch your arms out wide,
،فيما يلي، اثني ركبتيكِ وابسطي ذراعيكِ
and bring your hands together above your head.
واجمعي يديكِ معاً فوق رأسكِ
Above your head!
!فوق رأسكِ